ALIYA ROMANOV

123 Your Street, Boston, MA 12345 aliyaromanov@exdmple.com (123) 456-7890

A Chemist with five years of experience, specializing in product development, synthetic chemistry, research and development (R&D), and project management, A proven track record of leading high-impact matrixed teams to create new chemical Formulations for new products.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE (M.S.) CHEMISTRY

Boston University, Boston, MA May 2016 - May 2018

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.S.) CHEMISTRY Boston University, Boston, MA

September 2012 - May 2016

KEY SKILLS

- · Organic Chemistry
- Product Development
- Laboratory Operations
- Research and Development (R&D)
- Project Management

CERTIFICATIONS

- Specialist in Chemistry (ASCP), 2018
- Certified Chemical Engineer
 (CCE), 2016

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CHEMIST

Sonoma Ink Corp., Boston, MA May 2018 - Present

- Lead the characterization of polymer for ink Formulations in a high-volume lab environment for the development of a new ink product line valued at S2M and partner with manufacturing teams to improve production capacity by 15%
- Manage a team of 15 chemists, technicians, and engineers, coordinate projects from initial conception to commercialization, and provide ongoing coaching and mentorship
- Create presentations on research data and attend meetings with project teams and stakeholders to review project milestones, roadblocks, and research Findings

CHEMIST

New England Cosmetics Inc., Boston, MA May 2016 — May 2018

- Supported R&D activities For the development of skincare, sun protection, and hair care product lines, evaluated materials to ensure optimal Formulations, and identified opportunities to refine existing product Formulas
- Coordinated with cross-functional teams throughout the product development lifecycle, including interfacing with manufacturers to scale production capabilities